<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>2022 on mailcow: dockerized - Blog</title><link>https://mailcow.email/tags/2022/</link><description>Recent content in 2022 on mailcow: dockerized - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</managingEditor><webMaster>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 09:30:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mailcow.email/tags/2022/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🎄🐄 Moocember Update 2022 - MUH-I Update (Bootstrap 5)</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-12/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Dec 2022 09:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-12/</guid><description>Introduction Moohoo everyone!
To end the chaotic year 2022 in a worthy manner, the time has finally come. The long awaited Bootstrap 5 update is finally here!
As already mentioned in some posts, this update marks only the turning point of the mailcow UI, because the new base (Bootstrap 5) will offer us many new possibilities and scope for new features in the future.
Because of the Bootstrap update the old UI was completely renewed and ported to the new version.</description></item><item><title>🚚🐄 Moovember Update 2022 - Sogo 5.8.0, Rspamd 3.4.0 and PHP 8.1 Update | Revision B</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-11a/</link><pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2022 09:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-11a/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Moohoo everyone!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Due to the &lt;del>2022-11a&lt;/del> 2022-11b update, here are the changelogs of the &lt;del>2022-11a&lt;/del> 2022-11b update and the changes of the major version (2022-11).&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>We´ve released 2022-11b already!&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>⚠️ 2022-10a | Critical stability update ⚠️</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-10a/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 09:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-10a/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Moohoo everyone!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yesterday (on 25th October 2022) we´ve released the 2022-10 update.
This Update here contains a critical error with the spam filtering for several (not many), which ensures that no more emails can go out or come in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We strongly advise you to update your mailcow installation which is updated with the 2022-10 update!!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🌰🐄 Mooctober Update 2022 - Translation overhaul + multithreaded backup/restore script update</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-10/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 10:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-10/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;strong>Moohoo everyone!&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We are moving in big steps towards the end of the year and despite the fact that the Bootstrap 5 UI update is still a bit more delayed (thanks for your patience by the way!) here is another small but nice mailcow update for you today.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>🍂🐄 Mootember Update 2022 - Quarantine &amp; Swagger UI Fix Update - Revision A | Changes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-09/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Sep 2022 12:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-09/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="2022-09a-release-30th-september-2022">2022-09a (Release: 30th September 2022)&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Changes:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>The Twig template system on which mailcow is based has been updated to version 3.4.3 and closes &lt;a href="https://github.com/advisories/GHSA-52m2-vc4m-jj33">CVE-2022-39261&lt;/a>.&lt;br>
&lt;strong>Attention: This CVE is not critical for all mailcow users but only serves to update the packages&lt;/strong>.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>🌊🐄 Amoogust Update 2022 - The Nightly Build Switch Update (Revision B) | Changes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08b/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 10:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08b/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
A small but important update for or against the current SOGo Sieve/mail sending problems is here!
We received countless messages about this and implemented a fix within tis update, which hopefully solves the problem for everyone.
For those who are interested: It&amp;rsquo;s probably related to the IPv6 support introduced in SOGo 5.7.1 and the internal IPv6 connectivity of mailcow´s Docker containers, which triggered connectivity issues with SOGo.
Yeah&amp;hellip; however, this bug should be fixed now.</description></item><item><title>Our new addition: The new mailcow UI (MUH-I) in Bootstrap 5</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/nightly-tests-bs5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 09:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/nightly-tests-bs5/</guid><description>It took long enough, but here it is finally: The new mailcow UI!
Currently it&amp;rsquo;s still exclusively in the nightly builds because we want to optimize the UI.
And that&amp;rsquo;s where you come in! Because we want to make the UI as user friendly as possible and improve not only the framework but also the usability.
So if there was one thing that always bothered you so far, please let us know!</description></item><item><title>🌊🐄 Amoogust Update 2022 - The Nightly Build Switch Update | Changes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 10:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
Yeah, a August Update in September&amp;hellip; kinda sus if you ask me!
This time there are even some changes regarding the Update sources! So stay curious.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start quite gently for the time being:
Stable changes (stable branch) OAuth clients and app passwords are now accepted again for Cal/CardDav connections. #4685 by @FreddleSpl0it SOGo has been updated to 5.7.1 (Complete changelog here) receives in mailcow stack container version: mailcow/sogo:1.</description></item><item><title>☀️🐄 Mooly Update 2022 - Revision A | Changes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 10:32:00 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07a/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
We&amp;rsquo;ve released an short update that improved the API and brings a new version of ClamAV (0.105.1).
Note: The update to ClamAV 0.105.1 is recommended by ClamAV as a security update (See ClamAV Update article)
Once again summarized what changes:
The schema of the domain section of the API has been adjusted and improved. Automatic GitHub actions for building the latest container versions has been set up (currently not used productively).</description></item><item><title>☀️🐄 Mooly Update 2022 - TFA Flow Update | Changelog</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 08:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
It&amp;rsquo;s update time once again, a little later than before (I&amp;rsquo;ll get into that a bit later) but still packed with some changes:
TFA Changes 2FA is now also possible for mailbox users in the UI (previously this was reserved for administrators). Also, it is now possible to enable multiple 2FA options for an account. Note: Only one is used, which is selected by the user. There is a nice new menu at to select the available 2FA options.</description></item><item><title>🌕🐄 Moone Update 2022 - The Docker Compose v2 Update (Part I) | Changes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 12:07:10 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-06/</guid><description>Moohoo everybody!
Today we have put together a big fat update package for you again, which besides general container updates brings one big change:
Docker Compose v2 support!!!
But let&amp;rsquo;s start with the small stuff first:
Minor changes ClamAV is now using version 0.105 (the latest at release time). Postfix has been updated to version 3.5.6. netfilter, acme, dockerapi, olefy, watchdog, unbound and phpfpm have been updated to Alpine Linux 3.</description></item><item><title>⚠️ 2022-05d Important Security Update! ⚠️</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 16:03:56 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05d/</guid><description>Hello all,
Yesterday we received an important tip about a critical security vulnerability in mailcow (thanks again for that). It affects IMAPSYNC and gives access to administration rights in the mailcow UI and API.
It is strongly recommended to install the update as soon as possible to prevent exploitation.
As always please take a look at the GitHub Release: https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/releases/tag/2022-05d
The update does not remove any important functionality from mailcow or IMAPSYNC!</description></item><item><title>🌌🐮 Mooay 2022 Update - The Tag Update | Revision C - Changelog</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:22:00 +0200</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05/</guid><description>2022-05c It´s us again again!
This time we´ve published the 2022-05c Update which is a very small one.
It changed the API a bit again. This time for security reasons.
Head over to GitHub to see the full changelog: https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/releases/tag/2022-05c
Stay healthy
Niklas
2022-05b It´s us again!
Today we have a small API Fix Update which focus mainly on the UI.
As some of you reported the API Calls for Domains/Mailboxes don´t work anymore if there is no Tag set.</description></item><item><title>⚠️ Important Information about the 2022-04 Update ⚠️</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/2022-04-info/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:01:00 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/2022-04-info/</guid><description>Yesterday we released the 2022-04 update (Moopril) which included a change in the NGINX configuration. During the same day we received a message that SOGo would not work since the update, more precisely the login.
So we released an update yesterday evening around 23:00 (German summertime) which solves this problem in most cases.
Please update your mailcow via the update.sh Script as soon as possible to use SOGo as usual again.</description></item><item><title>🐄🐰Moopril 2022 - ClamAV, Rspamd, SOGo Update | Patchnotes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 10:42:00 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-04/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
The April update is here with a bunch of new stuff for your flawless E-Mail Flow.
This month we have 3 component updates (ClamAV, SOGo and Rspamd) and a few minor fixes which are as follows:
Major Changes We have updated SOGo in the mailcow stack to 5.5.1. Besides the SOGo fixes (see here) the mailcow database structure has been tweaked a bit to be ready for the upcoming 5.</description></item><item><title>🐄💮 Moorch Update 2022 – Revision A | Patchnotes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 22:29:00 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03a/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
We have released an impromptu bug fix update that fixes a few minor bugs and graphical issues.
These are only minor changes this time, but as the saying goes, &amp;ldquo;Every little bit helps&amp;rdquo;.
We have moved the version footer back to the correct position. Faithful to the motto: Stay were you are! We have improved the release tag handling with the version footer. The backup and restore script now uses Debian Bullseye instead of Buster.</description></item><item><title>🐄💮 Moorch Update 2022 – ClamAV, Dovecot &amp; Olefy Update | Patchnotes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:48:00 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone, March is here and by the end of the month it will be spring again. Surely the last few days were as scary for you as they were for us.
🇺🇦 Ukraine, we are standing with you!
Let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the March update of our mailcow. Spoilers ahead, the March update is not that full and extensive but there are some nice updates included in terms of long term (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you ClamAV and Olefy!</description></item><item><title>📘New: The mailcow Docs now also speak German! 📘 - mailcow Docs 2.0 Release Notes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/docs-update-2.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 14:53:25 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/docs-update-2.0/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone! It&amp;rsquo;s Friday then Then Saturday, Sunday (what?)
We have an exciting news to share with you!
We present you the newly released mailcow: dockerized Docs 2.0!
Not much may have changed at first glance (you would think) but under the hood a lot has changed!
So we present you from today:
Multi-language support (English and German are supported and updated by Servercow itself ) Light-/Darkmode New organized structure (interesting for contributors) All in all a remake of the existing docs.</description></item><item><title>📰🐄 Jan(moo)uary Update 2022 - Revision A (2022-01a) 🪲 | Patchnotes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-01a/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 15:28:32 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-01a/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone.
Today we are releasing the first hotfix for the 2022-01 Update.
This has changed:
Additions: We´ve added a Version Tag which is located at the bottom of the mailcow UI (It now shows the current release tag you are on!) Isn´t that crazy? (https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/pull/4437) Changes: The passwordless SOGo Authentication is now supporting calender invitations and calender/contact subscriptions (https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/pull/4439) The Autoreply Schedule for SOGo has been changed from 24h to 5m (https://github.</description></item><item><title>Is it a 🐦? Is it a ✈️? No it's the mailcow on Twitter!</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/mailcow-twitter/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Jan 2022 12:33:09 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/mailcow-twitter/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
Our dear mailcow has taken the plunge into social media: Twitter!
There she will provide you with new release information or small hints about possible new features as well as general information about the mailcow project.
Of course you can also tweet about your experiences with mailcow. Just use the Twitter handle: @mailcow_email.
We look forward to getting in touch with you there and keeping you up to date.</description></item><item><title>📰🐄 Jan(moo)uary Update 2022 - The U2F --> WebAuthn (2FA) Update | Patchnotes</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-01/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Jan 2022 14:55:47 +0100</pubDate><author>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-01/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone, Niklas here with the latest changelog for our beloved mailcow email software!
This month there is a big chunk of changes, some of them even very important regarding 2FA, but more about that later.
First of all we would like to thank you for your loyalty and cooperation, because without you the mailcow project wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where it is now ❤️
We would also like to apologize for the fact that we are only now releasing a new update (master branch release), because some of the fixes included in this update (SOGo e.</description></item></channel></rss>