<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>News - Tag - mailcow: dockerized - Blog</title><link>https://mailcow.email/tags/news/</link><description>News - Tag | mailcow: dockerized - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 16:00:10 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mailcow.email/tags/news/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>🌟 Important News on the Continued Development of mailcow</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2024/development-change/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 16:00:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2024/development-change/</guid><description>Dear mailcow Community,
mailcow continues to enjoy increasing popularity, and we are, of course, delighted by this.
To continue delivering the necessary quality in the project and always meet the community&amp;rsquo;s expectations, we have adjusted and extended our update intervals accordingly. This allows us to maintain the high quality of updates for bug and feature requests.
Going forward, we will tie the update intervals to the significance of the scope of the requests.</description></item><item><title>🤔🔒🐮 What's up? - LDAP Integration</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2024/whats-up-ldap/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 11:10:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2024/whats-up-ldap/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><strong>Moohoo everyone!</strong></p>
<p>As already announced on social media channels, today we are serving you a new edition of our section: <code>What's up?</code>.</p>
<p>Today, we are explicitly discussing a topic of burning interest to all of us: <strong>LDAP/OIDC Integration</strong> and the associated <strong>overhaul of the authentication system</strong>.</p>
<p>We have kept you updated in the past that we are feverishly working on integrating LDAP and OIDC. After all, this function is not without reason one of the most requested features for mailcow ever – and rightly so!</p>
<p>However, our plan was to release this whole thing in the first quarter of 2024 or maybe even around Christmas 2023. As you have noticed, both timelines could not be met&hellip;</p>]]></description></item><item><title>🤔🐮 What's up? - ARM64 Integration</title><link>https://mailcow.email/posts/2023/whats-up-arm64/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 09:15:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://mailcow.email/posts/2023/whats-up-arm64/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
It has been more than a month since you heard from us and today we have a shadowdrop as an update.
Since we have a few things to discuss and want to communicate directly in the future, we came up with a section called What&amp;rsquo;s up?.
Today we start with the first topic, namely ARM64:
Originally we announced to have mailcow ARM64 ready by June 2023. Obviously that didn&amp;rsquo;t work out so well.</description></item></channel></rss>