<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>2021 - Tag - mailcow: dockerized - Blog</title>
        <link>http://news.mailcow.email/tags/2021/</link>
        <description>2021 - Tag - mailcow: dockerized - Blog</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</managingEditor>
            <webMaster>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 08:49:44 &#43;0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://news.mailcow.email/tags/2021/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>⚠️ Important informations about log4j exploit ⚠️</title>
    <link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/log4j-dec2022/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 13 Dec 2021 08:49:44 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Niklas Meyer</author>
    <guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/log4j-dec2022/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Moohoo everyone! Due to the recent accidents regarding the Java library log4j we would like to inform you, that your mailcow is NOT affected directly by this.
Yes, it is true, that the Solr Container is a Java application which is affected by the log4j security breach. BUT solr is NOT accessible from the outside of the mailcow stack!
For those who are worried we released a Solr Hotfix which is fixing the log4j issue with the simple flag +EXTRA_ARGS+=('-Dlog4j2.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🐄 Moovember 2021 - Patchnotes</title>
    <link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/moovember2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 03 Dec 2021 09:49:47 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>Niklas Meyer</author>
    <guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/moovember2021/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Moohoo everyone!
Niklas here to present you the latest news around our lovely mailcow :)
Let&rsquo;s get started, shall we?
 Major changes from November 2021 for the mailcow stack:  SOGo update to 5.3.0 Dovecot update to 2.3.17 ClamAV update to 0.103.4 [Web] Auto-generated app passwords for Apple configuration profiles  Please consider updating your mailcow stack to ensure a stable environment.
 All changes from November 2021 for the mailcow stack (newest to oldest): 30th November 2021:]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>🐄 Mooctober 2021 - the feldsam edition</title>
    <link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/mooctober2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Mon, 18 Oct 2021 21:55:47 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>André Peters</author>
    <guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/mooctober2021/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[A big thanks to Kristian Feldsam for integrating Twig. We are closer to Bootstrap 5 than ever. That&rsquo;s a big change we hope to finish soon.
Furthermore we introduce our new cold standby solution.
With this new script you are able to create a fully working, 1:1, consistent copy of your running mailcow without downtime.
Disaster recovery of a mailcow is as easy as switching IPs and running &ldquo;up -d&rdquo;.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>more, moore, moooore</title>
    <link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/moore_october21/</link>
    <pubDate>Fri, 01 Oct 2021 21:55:47 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>André Peters</author>
    <guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/moore_october21/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Girls, guys and cows,
Development is not stuck, we just have trouble handling many requests of new customers. Combined with cases of illness, vacation and the usual business we are really under stress.
We are also reworking the design a bit, that&rsquo;s a WIP and will take a while. The first new prints will probably be seen on our new cars @ tinc. We are very excited! There are also plans for a mailcow.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>From Peru with moo!</title>
    <link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/xubium_recommend/</link>
    <pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 20:13:47 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>André Peters</author>
    <guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/xubium_recommend/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Dear cows,
For organizations in Spanish-speaking countries I would recommend you check out Xubium.

They are a Latin-American company with expertise in mailcow that works with our infrastructure and support to provide a fully managed email service to medium and small businesses.
Xubium is an amazing company to work with, it has our recommendation by all means.]]></description>
</item>
<item>
    <title>mailcows updated between 25th August and 2nd September 2021 should be updated again</title>
    <link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/rspamd_memleak_sep2021/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 02 Sep 2021 20:19:57 &#43;0100</pubDate>
    <author>André Peters</author>
    <guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/rspamd_memleak_sep2021/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Hi,
If you updated your mailcow between 25th August and 2nd September 2021 you most likely encounter a settings map memory leak in Rspamd that was fixed just now.
Besides that, we also heavily reduced the map hammering with another change in the map generator.
Update time!
André]]></description>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
