<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - mailcow: dockerized - Blog</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/</link><description>All Posts | mailcow: dockerized - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</managingEditor><webMaster>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 12:09:01 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://news.mailcow.email/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The new Demos are here!</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/our-new-demos/</link><pubDate>Sat, 24 Sep 2022 12:09:01 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/our-new-demos/</guid><description><![CDATA[<div class="featured-image">
                <img src="https://news.mailcow.email/images/demo_thumb.png" referrerpolicy="no-referrer">
            </div><p>Moohoo everyone!</p>
<p>It´s finally time: Our new mailcow Demos are here and live for you to test!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>🌊🐄 Amoogust Update 2022 - The Nightly Build Switch Update (Revision B) | Changes</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08b/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 10:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08b/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
A small but important update for or against the current SOGo Sieve/mail sending problems is here!
We received countless messages about this and implemented a fix within tis update, which hopefully solves the problem for everyone.
For those who are interested: It&amp;rsquo;s probably related to the IPv6 support introduced in SOGo 5.7.1 and the internal IPv6 connectivity of mailcow´s Docker containers, which triggered connectivity issues with SOGo.
Yeah&amp;hellip; however, this bug should be fixed now.</description></item><item><title>Our new addition: The new mailcow UI (MUH-I) in Bootstrap 5</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/nightly-tests-bs5/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2022 09:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/nightly-tests-bs5/</guid><description>It took long enough, but here it is finally: The new mailcow UI!
Currently it&amp;rsquo;s still exclusively in the nightly builds because we want to optimize the UI.
And that&amp;rsquo;s where you come in! Because we want to make the UI as user friendly as possible and improve not only the framework but also the usability.
So if there was one thing that always bothered you so far, please let us know!</description></item><item><title>🌊🐄 Amoogust Update 2022 - The Nightly Build Switch Update | Changes</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 10:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-08/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
Yeah, a August Update in September&amp;hellip; kinda sus if you ask me!
This time there are even some changes regarding the Update sources! So stay curious.
Let&amp;rsquo;s start quite gently for the time being:
Stable changes (stable branch) OAuth clients and app passwords are now accepted again for Cal/CardDav connections. #4685 by @FreddleSpl0it SOGo has been updated to 5.7.1 (Complete changelog here ) receives in mailcow stack container version: mailcow/sogo:1.</description></item><item><title>☀️🐄 Mooly Update 2022 - Revision A | Changes</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07a/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Jul 2022 10:32:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07a/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
We&amp;rsquo;ve released an short update that improved the API and brings a new version of ClamAV (0.105.1).
Note: The update to ClamAV 0.105.1 is recommended by ClamAV as a security update (See ClamAV Update article) Once again summarized what changes:
The schema of the domain section of the API has been adjusted and improved. Automatic GitHub actions for building the latest container versions has been set up (currently not used productively).</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the new mailcow blog!</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/welcome-new-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 12:09:01 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/welcome-new-blog/</guid><description>Happy new day to you!
Welcome to the new blog page.
Some of you may have already stumbled across the site on Twitter or on Telegram in the last update announcement, but now here again officially!
Built with the fast and beautiful Static Site Generator Hugo and the LoveIt Theme, this site can keep up with WordPress and even outperform it.
What changes for all blog readers? Well, actually nothing. The only thing that changes is the URL (at least for now) instead of mailcow.</description></item><item><title>☀️🐄 Mooly Update 2022 - TFA Flow Update | Changelog</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 08:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
It&amp;rsquo;s update time once again, a little later than before (I&amp;rsquo;ll get into that a bit later) but still packed with some changes:
TFA Changes 2FA is now also possible for mailbox users in the UI (previously this was reserved for administrators). Also, it is now possible to enable multiple 2FA options for an account. Note: Only one is used, which is selected by the user. There is a nice new menu at to select the available 2FA options.</description></item><item><title>🌕🐄 Moone Update 2022 - The Docker Compose v2 Update (Part I) | Changes</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 12:07:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-06/</guid><description>Moohoo everybody!
Today we have put together a big fat update package for you again, which besides general container updates brings one big change:
Docker Compose v2 support!!!
But let&amp;rsquo;s start with the small stuff first:
Minor changes ClamAV is now using version 0.105 (the latest at release time). Postfix has been updated to version 3.5.6. netfilter, acme, dockerapi, olefy, watchdog, unbound and phpfpm have been updated to Alpine Linux 3.</description></item><item><title>⚠️ 2022-05d Important Security Update! ⚠️</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 16:03:56 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05d/</guid><description>Hello all,
Yesterday we received an important tip about a critical security vulnerability in mailcow (thanks again for that). It affects IMAPSYNC and gives access to administration rights in the mailcow UI and API.
It is strongly recommended to install the update as soon as possible to prevent exploitation.
As always please take a look at the GitHub Release: https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/releases/tag/2022-05d The update does not remove any important functionality from mailcow or IMAPSYNC!</description></item><item><title>🌌🐮 Mooay 2022 Update - The Tag Update | Revision C - Changelog</title><link>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:22:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>https://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05/</guid><description>2022-05c It´s us again again!
This time we´ve published the 2022-05c Update which is a very small one.
It changed the API a bit again. This time for security reasons.
Head over to GitHub to see the full changelog: https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/releases/tag/2022-05c Stay healthy
Niklas
2022-05b It´s us again!
Today we have a small API Fix Update which focus mainly on the UI.
As some of you reported the API Calls for Domains/Mailboxes don´t work anymore if there is no Tag set.</description></item></channel></rss>