<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>All Posts - mailcow: dockerized - Blog</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/</link><description>All Posts | mailcow: dockerized - Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</managingEditor><webMaster>info@servercow.de (Moohoo)</webMaster><lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 12:09:01 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://news.mailcow.email/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome to the new mailcow blog!</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/welcome-new-blog/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 12:09:01 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/welcome-new-blog/</guid><description>Happy new day to you!
Welcome to the new blog page.
Some of you may have already stumbled across the site on Twitter or on Telegram in the last update announcement, but now here again officially!
Built with the fast and beautiful Static Site Generator Hugo and the LoveIt Theme, this site can keep up with WordPress and even outperform it.
What changes for all blog readers? Well, actually nothing. The only thing that changes is the URL (at least for now) instead of mailcow.</description></item><item><title>☀️🐄 Mooly Update 2022 - TFA Flow Update | Changelog</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jul 2022 08:30:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-07/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
It&amp;rsquo;s update time once again, a little later than before (I&amp;rsquo;ll get into that a bit later) but still packed with some changes:
TFA Changes 2FA is now also possible for mailbox users in the UI (previously this was reserved for administrators). Also, it is now possible to enable multiple 2FA options for an account. Note: Only one is used, which is selected by the user. There is a nice new menu at to select the available 2FA options.</description></item><item><title>🌕🐄 Moone Update 2022 - The Docker Compose v2 Update (Part I) | Changes</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-06/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Jun 2022 12:07:10 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-06/</guid><description>Moohoo everybody!
Today we have put together a big fat update package for you again, which besides general container updates brings one big change:
Docker Compose v2 support!!!
But let&amp;rsquo;s start with the small stuff first:
Minor changes ClamAV is now using version 0.105 (the latest at release time). Postfix has been updated to version 3.5.6. netfilter, acme, dockerapi, olefy, watchdog, unbound and phpfpm have been updated to Alpine Linux 3.</description></item><item><title>⚠️ 2022-05d Important Security Update! ⚠️</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05d/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 May 2022 16:03:56 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05d/</guid><description>Hello all,
Yesterday we received an important tip about a critical security vulnerability in mailcow (thanks again for that). It affects IMAPSYNC and gives access to administration rights in the mailcow UI and API.
It is strongly recommended to install the update as soon as possible to prevent exploitation.
As always please take a look at the GitHub Release: https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/releases/tag/2022-05d The update does not remove any important functionality from mailcow or IMAPSYNC!</description></item><item><title>🌌🐮 Mooay 2022 Update - The Tag Update | Revision C - Changelog</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2022 09:22:00 +0200</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-05/</guid><description>2022-05c It´s us again again!
This time we´ve published the 2022-05c Update which is a very small one.
It changed the API a bit again. This time for security reasons.
Head over to GitHub to see the full changelog: https://github.com/mailcow/mailcow-dockerized/releases/tag/2022-05c Stay healthy
Niklas
2022-05b It´s us again!
Today we have a small API Fix Update which focus mainly on the UI.
As some of you reported the API Calls for Domains/Mailboxes don´t work anymore if there is no Tag set.</description></item><item><title>⚠️ Important Information about the 2022-04 Update ⚠️</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/2022-04-info/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2022 10:01:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/2022-04-info/</guid><description>Yesterday we released the 2022-04 update (Moopril) which included a change in the NGINX configuration. During the same day we received a message that SOGo would not work since the update, more precisely the login.
So we released an update yesterday evening around 23:00 (German summertime) which solves this problem in most cases.
Please update your mailcow via the update.sh Script as soon as possible to use SOGo as usual again.</description></item><item><title>🐄🐰Moopril 2022 - ClamAV, Rspamd, SOGo Update | Patchnotes</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-04/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 10:42:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-04/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
The April update is here with a bunch of new stuff for your flawless E-Mail Flow.
This month we have 3 component updates (ClamAV, SOGo and Rspamd) and a few minor fixes which are as follows:
Major Changes We have updated SOGo in the mailcow stack to 5.5.1. Besides the SOGo fixes (see here ) the mailcow database structure has been tweaked a bit to be ready for the upcoming 5.</description></item><item><title>🐄💮 Moorch Update 2022 – Revision A | Patchnotes</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03a/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Mar 2022 22:29:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03a/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone!
We have released an impromptu bug fix update that fixes a few minor bugs and graphical issues.
These are only minor changes this time, but as the saying goes, &amp;ldquo;Every little bit helps&amp;rdquo;.
We have moved the version footer back to the correct position. Faithful to the motto: Stay were you are! We have improved the release tag handling with the version footer. The backup and restore script now uses Debian Bullseye instead of Buster.</description></item><item><title>🐄💮 Moorch Update 2022 – ClamAV, Dovecot &amp; Olefy Update | Patchnotes</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Mar 2022 16:48:00 +0100</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/release-2022-03/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone, March is here and by the end of the month it will be spring again. Surely the last few days were as scary for you as they were for us.
🇺🇦 Ukraine, we are standing with you!
Let&amp;rsquo;s move on to the March update of our mailcow. Spoilers ahead, the March update is not that full and extensive but there are some nice updates included in terms of long term (I&amp;rsquo;m looking at you ClamAV and Olefy!</description></item><item><title>📘New: The mailcow Docs now also speak German! 📘 - mailcow Docs 2.0 Release Notes</title><link>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/docs-update-2.0/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Feb 2022 14:53:25 +0100</pubDate><author>Niklas Meyer</author><guid>http://news.mailcow.email/posts/2022/docs-update-2.0/</guid><description>Moohoo everyone! It&amp;rsquo;s Friday then Then Saturday, Sunday (what?)
We have an exciting news to share with you!
We present you the newly released mailcow: dockerized Docs 2.0!
Not much may have changed at first glance (you would think) but under the hood a lot has changed!
So we present you from today:
Multi-language support (English and German are supported and updated by Servercow itself ) Light-/Darkmode New organized structure (interesting for contributors) All in all a remake of the existing docs.</description></item></channel></rss>